Arcadio Díaz Quiñones Papers, circa 1944-2019 (bulk 1970-2012 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
Arcadio Díaz Quiñones Papers
circa 1944-2019
1970-2012
C0014
Princeton University Library. Special Collections. Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
Díaz Quiñones, Arcadio
The Arcadio Díaz Quiñones Papers consists chiefly of manuscripts and correspondence of the Puerto Rican professor of Spanish and Portuguese Languages and Cultures at Princeton University, Arcadio Díaz Quiñones (1940-), as well as a selection of manuscripts by others. The collection focuses on Puerto Rican and Cuban literature, but also provides insight into the literature and politics of other parts of Latin America.
28 boxes 2 items
Arcadio Díaz Quiñones is Professor Emeritus of Spanish and Portuguese at Princeton University.
For more detailed information, see: https://dof.princeton.edu/about/clerk-faculty/emeritus/arcadio-diaz-quinones
This collection consists chiefly of manuscripts and correspondence of Arcadio Díaz Quiñones. Some of the manuscripts of Díaz Quiñones are transcripts of unpublished interviews with writers. Included are the autograph and typescript manuscripts of his interviews with Luis Rafael Sánchez (partially published in the journal Sin Nombre [San Juan, P.R.], 1981), and Cintio Vitier (published as Cintio Vitier, la memoria integradora [San Juan, P.R.: Editorial Sin Nombre, 1987]). The bulk of the collection is made up of correspondence, predominantly between Díaz Quiñones and Puerto Rican and Cuban writers, but there are also letters from writers, artists, and scholars from other Latin American countries, Spain, and the United States, as well as from former students. Correspondents in the collection include Ricardo Piglia, Ángel Rama, Joseph Sommers, Rosario Ferré, Edwin Figueroa, José Luis González, Lorenzo Homar, René Marqués, Antonio Martorell, Ángel G. Quintero Rivera, Nilita Vientós Gastón, Ambrosio Fornet, Fina García Marruz, and Cintio Vitier. Notable as well is the correspondence with the Centro de Estudios de la Realidad Puertorriqueña (CEREP) and the Asociación Puertorriqueña de Profesores Universitarios (APPU). Also present is a small amount of printed materials, including event fliers and programs, and a copy of a map annotated by Argentine author Juan José Saer.
Furthermore, the collection contains a selection of works by others that were sent to Díaz Quiñones. These manuscripts include the writings of the Puerto Ricans Vanessa Droz, Rosario Ferré, Lorenzo Homar, José Luis González, René Marqués, and Luis Rafael Sánchez, and Cubans Víctor Fowler and Fina García Marruz.
The following standard abbreviations, or their variations, are used to identify materials in this collection: ALS = autograph letter signed, TLS = typed letter signed, ACS = autograph card signed, AMsS = autograph manuscript signed, and TMsS = typed manuscript signed.
Organized into the following series:
Material within each section is arranged in accession order.
Material in Series 4, Box 19 is restricted until 2030.
Gift of Arcadio Diaz-Quiñones.
No appraisal information is available.
A manuscript found in draft form in the collection came to print in the following publication: Arcadio Díaz Quiñones, Cintio Vitier, la memoria integradora (San Juan, P.R.: Editorial Sin Nombre, 1987).
González, José Luis, -- 1926- -- Correspondence.; González, José Luis, -- 1926- -- Manuscripts.; Homar, Lorenzo -- Correspondence.; Sánchez, Luis Rafael -- Interviews.; Vitier, Cintio, -- 1921- -- Interviews.; Authors, Cuban -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Critics -- Puerto Rico -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Cuban literature -- 20th century.; Dramatists, Puerto Rican -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Latin American literature -- 20th century.; Novelists, Puerto Rican -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Puerto Rican literature -- 20th century.; Poets, Cuban -- 20th century -- Interviews.; Poets, Puerto Rican -- 20th century -- Interviews.; Cuba -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Puerto Rico -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Fliers (printed matter).; Programs (documents).; Latin American literature
- Series 1: Writings, 1970-1987; 2 boxes
  This series consists of manuscripts of interviews by Díaz Quiñones with different authors, such as José Luis González, Cintio Vitier, and Luis Rafael Sánchez, as well as several essays and literary reviews by Díaz Quiñones.
  This is arranged into subseries by acquisition number.
  - AM 84-35, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Ms about Ángel Quintero Alfaro, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Ms about Antonio Martorell, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - "Conversación con José Luis González": Ms, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - "Quemando belleza, suben de nivel los llanos": Ms, dates not examined; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 4)
    - "Laudo": Certamen de ensayo [ Claridad], dates not examined; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 4)
  - AM 84-35A and AM 1996-25, 1980-1981; 7 folders
    - Interview of Cintio Vitier by Arcadio Díaz Quiñones, 1980; 5 folders
      Published as Cintio Vitier, la memoria integradora (San Juan, P.R.: Editorial Sin Nombre, 1987).
      - Notepads containing transcripts of interview sessions, Arcadio Díaz Quiñones and Cintio Vitier, undated; Autograph manuscripts 2 folders (Folder 1-2)
      - "Cintio Vitier. Conversación con Cintio Vitier,", 1980; 3 folders
        - TMsS with holograph corrections, 1980; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - TMs (Xerox) with holograph corrections, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - TMsS with holograph corrections, undated; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 5)
        - "Segunda parte" and "Tercera parte," TMss (Xeroxes), dates not examined; 1 folder (partial) (Folder 5)
    - "Juan Ramón Jiménez: diario de un poeta", 1981; 1 folder
      - Screenplay for a film, 1981; Typed manuscripts (Xerox) and printed material 1 folder (Folder 6)
        Produced by the Division of Continuing Education, Rio Piedras campus, University of Puerto Rico.
    - "El oficio y la memoria: Luis Rafael Sánchez", 1981 April-June; 1 folder
      - Reprint of article published in Sin Nombre, San Juan, P.R., Vol. XII, No. 1, 1981 April-June; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - AM 2005-100, 1970-1987; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous essays and reviews, 1970-1987; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1959-2019; 17 boxes (1 partial) 2 items
  This series consists of both personal and professional correspondence sent to Díaz Quiñones by artists, scholars, and academic institutions. The sub-series within this series are organized by accession, and then alphabetically by correspondent. Two folders of unprocessed additional correspondence are located at the end of the "General" part of the accessions of 1998. At the end of the alphabetical listing of names in the 2004 accession, there are several folders containing Díaz Quiñones' correspondence and assorted materials on selected topics and various universities, as well as a small selection of memorabilia. Three folders of memorabilia, including conference and event flyers and articles, are likewise included at the end of the 2005 accession. In later accessions, the folders of memorabilia and those containing Díaz Quiñones' materials on selected topics have been placed in Series 4.
  Arranged into subseries by acquisition number.
  - AM 84-35, 1961-1982; 1 box
    - Abreu Adorno, Manuel, 1975-1978; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Albornoz, Aurora de, 1971; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Alegría, Ricardo E, 1981; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Álvarez Nazario, Manuel, 1971-1972; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Aranguren, José Luis L, 1968; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Arjona, Jaime Homero, 1965-1966; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Armistead, Samuel G, 1973; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Ateneo Puertorriqueño, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      [correspondence with accompanying printed matter]
    - Báez, Myrna, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Bataillon, Marcel, 1970; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Benítez, Marimar, 1982; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Buchanan, Ann, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Bulnes, José M, 1964-1971; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Castro, Américo, 1970; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - CEREP (Centro de Estudios de la Realidad Puertorriqueña), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Colón, Enrique, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Congreso de la Nueva Narrativa Hispanoamericana, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Díaz Valcárcel, Emilio, 1967; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Droz, Vanessa, 1971-1981; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Echeverría, José, 1969-1979; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Enjuto, Jorge, 1967-1974; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Feito, José, 1965; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Ferré, Rosario, 1972-1982; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Figueroa, Edwin, 1964-1968; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - Gili Gaya, Samuel, 1961-1963; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - González, José Luis, 1974-1982; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - González, Lydia Milagros, 1982; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - Guillén, Jorge, 1969-1970; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - Guinness, Gerald, 1982; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Hernández, Orlando José, 1971-1981; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Homar, Lorenzo, 1968-1972; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - Lida, Raimundo, 1969-1970; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - López Ramírez, Tomás, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - Marqués, René, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - Martorell, Antonio, 1980; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Porras Cruz, Jorge Luis, 1964-1970; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - Rama, Ángel, 1969-1980; 1 folder (Folder 37)
    - Rama, Carlos, 1970; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - Roa Bastos, Augusto, 1976; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - Sánchez, Luis Rafael, 1962-1980; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - Sommers, Joseph, 1966-1979; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Soto, Pedro Juan, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 42)
    - Tierno Galván, Enrique, 1970; 1 folder (Folder 43)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico, 1978; 1 folder (Folder 44)
  - AM 84-35A, undated; 1 box
    - Asociación Puertorriqueña de Profesores Universitarios, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Casa Nacional de la Cultura, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Colegio de Abogados de Puerto Rico, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Facultad de Humanidades de la Universidad de Puerto Rico, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - González, Emilio, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - AM 84-35A, 1970-1984; 2 boxes
    - Allen, Charlie, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Baker, Edward, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cardenal, Ernesto: TLS (Xerox), 1974; 1 box (partial)
    - Casa de la Américas [Cruz-Luis, Adolfo], dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Centro de Estudios de la Realidad Puertorriqueña (CEREP), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Chávez Alfaro, Lisandro and Echeandía, Servando, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ediciones Huracán: printed material, 1981; 1 box (partial)
      [See also Rivera Izcoa, Carmín]
    - Fabra, Gustavo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Fernández Retamar, Roberto: 2 TLsS, 1973; 1979; 1 box (partial)
    - Ferré, Rosario: TLS, 1973ACS, 1981printed material, 1983, 1 box (partial)
    - Forcione, Alban, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Franco, Jean, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - García Marruz, Fina: 2 ALsS, 1979; 1 box (partial)
    - Garrido, Ángel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Gelpí, Juan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Glantz, Margo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - González, José Luis: ALS, TLS, 1979; 1981; 1 box (partial)
    - de Granda, Germán, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Guinness, Gerald, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Hernández, Orlando, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Hirschman, Sara, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Homar, Lorenzo: 8 ALsS, 1982-1984; 1 box (partial)
    - Homar, Susan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Irby, James: 2 ALsS, 6 TLsS, 1970-1982; 1 box (partial)
    - López-Baralt, Merce, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Maldonado, Alex W., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Maldonado, Ángel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Márquez, Roberto, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Márquez Villanueva, Francisco, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Martín, José Luis, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Mateos, José, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Méndez-Clark, Ronald, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Mermall, Thomas, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Mestas, Juan E., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Molloy, Sylvia: 2 TLsS, 1973; 1978; 1 box (partial)
    - Nantes, Marie Jo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Navarro, Pablo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Oviedo, José Miguel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Parra, Nicanor: ALS, 1973; 1 box (partial)
    - Predmore, Michael, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Quijano, Aníbal, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ramírez, Sergio: ACS, 1976; poems of Carlos Martínez Rivas, TMs (thermofax), 1970s, 15 pp., 1 box (partial)
    - Ramos Otero, Manuel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Reyes Dávila, Marcos, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rivera, Carlos Rafael, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rivera Izcoa, Carmín [Ediciones Huracán], dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Romo Arregui, J., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ruffinelli, Jorge, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Saporta, Sol, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Traba, Marta: TLS, 1976; 1 box (partial)
    - Trigo Tió, Enrique, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Universidad de Puerto Rico. Depto. de Estudios Hispánicos, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Vargas Llosa, Mario: TLS, 1981; 1 box (partial)
    - Vázquez Arce, Carmen, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Vicens de Madrazo, Nimia, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Vitier, Cintio: ALsS, 2 ACS, 1975-1980; 1 box (partial)
    - Winslow, Cal, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Zamora Vicente, Alonso, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Zervigón, Pedro, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
  - AM 1998-17 and AM 1998-31, 1971-1997; 2 boxes 2 items
    - Antelo, Raúl, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Aponte, Samuel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Aponte Alsina, Marta, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - de Armas, Emilio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Avellaneda, Andrés, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Benítez Rojo, Antonio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Borinsky, Alicia, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Brioso, Jorge, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cairo, Ana, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Caparrós, Martín, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cedrón, Juan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Djurić, Djušan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Duchesne, Juan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Echavarría, Arturo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Echeverría, José, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Eguía, Beba (Marta), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ellrich, Robert, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ferré, Rosario: TLS, 2 ALsS, 2 ACsS, 1985-1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Fornet, Ambrosio: TLS, 2 ALsS, 2 ACsS, 1985-1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Forster, Ricardo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Fowler [Calzada], Víctor, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Fradera, Josep, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Funes, Reynaldo: 18 ALsS, 1 TLS, 1994 July-1997 June; 1 box (partial)
    - García, Gervasio L., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - García Marruz, Fina: ALS, 1981; 2 autograph poems, 1979, 1 box (partial)
    - Garramuño, Florencia, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Gelpí, Juan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Glantz, Margo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - González, Eduardo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - González, José Luis: TLS, 1984; 1 box (partial)
    - Gramuglio, María Teresa, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Hidalgo, Ibrahim, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Homar, Lorenzo: 15 ALsS, 1984-1994; untitled manuscript, AMs (Xerox), 1980s, 17 pp., 1 box (partial)
    - Iglesias, Alfonso, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Iglesias, Marial, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Kirkpatrick, Gwen, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Lewis, Gordon K.: TLS, 1974; 1 box (partial)
    - López Adorno, Pedro, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Lugo-Ortiz, Agnes, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Marichal, Sylvia, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Millones, Luis, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Montaldo, Graciela, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Montero, Oscar, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Morales, Ángel Luis, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Moreno Fraginals, Manuel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Morán, Francisco, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Osborne, Robert E. and Otero, Roberto, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Pérez-Marín, Carmen Ivette, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Piglia, Ricardo: 6 TLsS, 1986-1997; 1 box (partial)
    - Prieto, Antonio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Quintero, Juan Carlos, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Quintero-Rivera, Ángel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Quiza Moreno, Ricardo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rama, Ángel: 4 TLsS, 1977-1981; 1 box (partial)
    - Ramírez, Sergio: TLS (Xerox), 1991; 1 box (partial)
    - Ramos, Julio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Ramos Collado, Lilliana: ALS, 1978; 1 box (partial)
    - Ríos Avila, Rubén, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - del Risco, Enrique, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rodríguez, Eugenio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rodríguez, Pedro Pablo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rodríguez-González, Pedro, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rodríguez, Rafael, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Rojas, Rafael, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Sábato, Hilda, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez, Luis Rafael: 4 TLsS, 2 ALsS, 1980-1995; 1 box (partial)
    - Sánchez-Vidal, Agustín, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Santí, Enrico Mario, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Sarlo, Beatriz: 2 TLsS, 3 ALsS, 1992; 1 box (partial)
    - Sárraga, Raquel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Schmitt, John, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Scott, Rebecca, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Sepúlveda, Arnaldo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Sierra, Ernesto, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Silén, Iván: TLS, 1981; 1 box (partial)
    - Sin Nombre, dates not examined; 1 item
      [See Vientós Gastón, Nilita]
    - Sommers, Joseph, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Terán, Oscar, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Tineo, Gabriela, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Torres Morales, José Antonio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - del Toro, Carlos, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Traba, Marta: TNS, undated, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Vargas Llosa, Álvaro: 3 TLsS, 2 TLs (Xeroxes), 1983-1994; 1 box (partial)
    - Varo, Carlos, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Vázquez, Hugo: 10 ALsS, 1994 June-1995 August; 1 box (partial)
    - Venegas, Carlos, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Vera-León, Antonio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Vientós Gastón, Nilita: TLS, TL (carbon), TLS (Xerox), 1986-1988; 1 box (partial)
    - Vitier, Cintio: autograph poem, 1979; 2 TLsS, 6 ALsS, 1981-1987, 1 box (partial)
    - Zavala, Iris: 2 TLsS, 1 ALS, 1971; 1 box (partial)
    - Additional correspondence, received 9/29/97 [AM 1998-31], dates not examined; 1 box (1 partial)
      - Aponte - Zanetti, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
      - Unsorted, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
  - AM 2004-177, 1965-1983; 2 boxes
    - Adelman, Jeremy, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Adorno, Rolena, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Agrait, Luis (Puerto Rico), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Aguilar, Gonzalo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Alicea, Dennis, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Allen, Marnie, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Altamirano, Carlos, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Andreu-Iglesias, César (Puerto Rico), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Antelo, Antonio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Antelo, Raúl, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Aponte Alsina, Marta (Puerto Rico), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Aragunde, Rafael, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Armas, Emilio de (Cuba), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Avance 1972 (Puerto Rico), 1 box (partial)
    - Ayacucho, Biblioteca, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Barrera, Trinidad, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bejel, Emilio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Benítez-Rojo, Antonio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Berensztein, Sergio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bernabé, Mónica, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bernecker, Walter L., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Betancourt, Ingrid, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bhabha, Homi, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bhatia, Eduardo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Binder, Wolfgang (Germany), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bonilla, Frank (Puerto Rico), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bowen, William G., dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Bratosevich, Nicolás, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Britt, Christopher, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Brombert, Victor, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Buscaglia, José, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cairo, Ana, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Camacho de Schmidt, Aurora, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Campuzano, Luisa, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Carbonell, Jorge (Puerto Rico), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cárdenas, Cuauhtémoc, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Carrión, Juan Manuel, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Casanovas, Joan, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Castañeda, Miriam (Chile), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Castro-Klarén, Sara, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cátedra, Ediciones (Madrid), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - CEREP (Centro de Estudios de la Realidad Puertorriqueña), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cerrutii, Lucia (Italy), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Chejfec, Sergio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cincotta, Héctor Dante, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Clark, Adela, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cobo Borda, Juan Gustavo, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Concha, Jaime, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Corbett, Barbara, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cornejo Polar, Antonio, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cortés, Hipólito (Puerto Rico), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Coss, Luis Fernando, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Crescioni, Gladys, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cruz-Malavé, Arnaldo (Puerto Rico), dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Cubano, Astrid, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Curbelo, Irene, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Darnton, Robert, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Dash, Michael, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)
    - Dávila López, Grace, dates not examined; 1 box (partial)